Changhui (Cindy) McReynolds

Mobile: 832-466-8475 cindyhui546@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/Cindy452

Website: https://cindy-coding.herokuapp.com/

I am a self-taught web developer with an eagerness to learn and grow. I'm currently an administrative assistant in the construction field and hold a Chinese teaching certification from my bachelor's program, however after several years I realized I wanted to make a change and in 2020 while between jobs I dedicated 8+ hours a day from July 2020 to March 2021 to teaching myself new skills that can be of value in the software industry. Though I am currently working now, I continue to invest my free time to further my studies in programming and computer science. I am looking forward to finding a full-time or part-time position where I can offer my existing skills and talents to help my future employer, while also having the opportunity to learn and grow new skills along the way.

Experience

Allied Stone Inc., Jersey Village, Texas, USA

Warehouse administrative assistant

March 2021- Current

- Receive and transfer slabs and sinks from company's different branches
- Provide administrative support to leadership and inventory management for the warehouse
- Scan, submit orders, and track inventory

Co.Lab - You Belong in Tech, online

Software Developer

Feb 2021– April 2021

- Developed against a MERN stack to build a product that helps people navigate the pre and post-retirement journey
- Worked and collaborated with a senior developer in pair-programming sessions and code reviews
- Practiced Agile Methodology including discussing scope, timelines, and feasibility in conjunction with a project manager and designer.
- Used discord to communicate and LettuceMeet to perform scheduling for team meetings
- Used Trello board to map user stories and Figma to share wireframes and mock-ups
- Used git for source control to track changes in the project

Allied Stone Inc., Jersey Village, Texas, USA

Final quote coordinator- Team leader

May 2017– Jan 2020

- Billing and collecting past due invoices from customers
- Generating final quotes for counter-top and cabinet orders
- Tested company's stone profit system and gave feedback

Worker at various English training centers

April 2016 – August 2016

English tutor: Taught English lessons to 8-12 years old students

Heng Ling Complementary School ., He Shun County, Shanxi, China

Student Teacher Internship

March 2015 - July 2015

Served as a student teacher for fourth grade students, taught science, math, Chinese, and English

Personal Projects

Full stack Nestful web application - https://nestful.netlify.app/

• Used JSON web tokens for sign in authentication

- Used react-router-dom for page navigation
- Used mongoDB to save user's credential information
- Used React material UI for front-end, Node.js for the back-end

React E-commercial clothing website - https://crow-clothing-store.netlify.app/

- Used firebase for google sign in authentication
- Used react-router-dom for navigating the page, redux for state management
- Used sass for styling
- Used stripe checkout to handle payments

Fullstack exercises tracker – https://cindy-exercise.herokuapp.com/

 Built responsive website with MERN stack using React, React-Router, Bootstrap, Axios, Node.js, Express & MongoDB

Fullstack face detection app - https://face-detections-app.herokuapp.com/

- Used React for front-end, Node.js, Express & postgreSQL for back-end and database
- Used Clarifai API to recognize faces from submitted images
- Used Bcrypt.js to hash passwords

Skills

- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Sass, Javascript, React, Redux, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, SQL, C#, ASP.NET Core, styled component
- Git, Github, VS Code, Visual Studio, Heroku, Netlify, WordPress, Postman
- Fluent in Chinese and English

Education

FreeCodeCamp, Zero To Mastery - online

July 2020 - present

- Responsive Web design developer certification
- Javascript Algorithms and Data Structures developer certification
- Completed Web Developer in 2021: Zero to Mastery roadmap
- Build 20+ single page web application and full-stack web application

Jinzhong University - Bachelors in English Education

Graduated July 2016

English CET-4 & CET-6 (listening, speaking, reading and writing), Chinese Teacher certification

Interests

Programming, English, Chinese, Western Culture, Travel, Singing, Reading, Learning new things, Exercise,
Cooking